Louise Nevelson
Archives of American Art, Smithsonian Institution
- Subject Files, 1955-1971, 1977-1978, Series 3:; (Box 3; 0.7 linear feet)
  - Federation of Modern Painters and Sculptors, 1961-1963 (Box 3, Folder 25)
  - Four O'Clock Forums, 1953-1955 (Box 3, Folder 26)
  - Galerie Jeanne Bucher, 1969 (Box 3, Folder 27)
  - Galleries, Various, 1962-1963 (Box 3, Folder 28)
  - Great Neck Public Schools, 1958 (Box 3, Folder 29)
  - Miscellaneous, 1959-1964, (3 folders) (Box 3, Folder 30-32)
  - Museum of Modern Art, 1959, 1962-1963 (Box 3, Folder 33)
  - National Association of Women Artists, 1959-1965 (Box 3, Folder 34)
  - Nevelson, Mike, 1961 (Box 3, Folder 35)
  - New York Society of Women Artists, undated (Box 3, Folder 36)
  - New York State Art Teachers Association, 1958, (Not scanned in entirety) (Box 3, Folder 37)
  - New York University, 1958, 1961, (Not scanned in entirety) (Box 3, Folder 38)
  - Notes on (Nevelson) Art Work and Bibliography, 1960-1961, (2 folders) (Box 3, Folder 39-40)
  - Notes, Memos, and Correspondence (Tom Kendall), 1960-1961 (Box 3, Folder 41)
  - Photograph Orders, 1959-1961 (Box 3, Folder 42)
  - Princeton University Conference, 1977-1978 (Box 3, Folder 43)
  - Queens College, 1958-1961 (Box 3, Folder 44)
  - Reviews, circa 1965 (Box 3, Folder 45)
  - Riverside Museum, 1956-1957 (Box 3, Folder 46)
  - Rockefeller Sculpture, 1961 (Box 3, Folder 47)
  - Scotsdale (Arizona), 1972 (Box 3, Folder 48)
  - Sculptor's Guild, 1956-1961 (Box 3, Folder 49)
  - Tamarind Lithography Workshop, 1963, (Not scanned in entirety) (Box 3, Folder 50)
  - Titles, undated (Box 3, Folder 51)
  - Wadsworth Atheneum, 1962 (Box 3, Folder 52)
- Business Records, 1946-1954, 1958-1962, Series 4:; (Boxes 3-5; 1.8 linear feet)
  Series consists of files stemming from Nevelson's business dealings with the Martha Jackson Gallery (her primary representative from 1958 to 1962) and other business matters, usually carried out by her assistant, Tom Kendall, on her behalf. Files include consignment receipts, statements, memos, correspondence, notes, inventories, disposition cards, notebooks, lists, and dummy pages for a Nevelson book (compiled from the text of an interview by Tal Streeter and photographs of Nevelson) that was never completed. Also included are scattered note cards and drawings kept by Nevelson, documenting certain early works and their disposition.
  The bulk of the files seem to relate to the large project of inventorying Nevelson's art work, including black wood constructions, white works, bronzes, etchings, and drawings, which was most likely carried out by Nevelson's assistant and gallery staff sometime in the early-1960s. Some inventories provide basic information about art works (including title, dates, dimensions, and so on). More detailed inventories, along with the lists, disposition cards, and notebooks which seem to have been used in compiling them, provide further information about the previous and/or current location, ownership, and disposition of art works. Some photographs and sketches of art work can be found on the disposition cards. Other files relate to the pricing, sale, and exhibition of Nevelson's art work.
  Files are arranged by format in rough chronological order. Related material can be found amongst the subject files.
  - Note Cards on Disposition of Certain Works (kept by Nevelson), 1946-1950 (Box 3, Folder 53)
  - Drawings of Terra Cotta Sculptures, 1948-1954 (Box 3, Folder 54)
  - Martha Jackson Gallery, 1958-1962, (4 folders) (Box 3, Folder 55-58)
  - Inventory of Works,1958-1960 (Box 3, Folder 59)
  - Nevelson Inventory (Inventory of Nevelson Works in Martha Jackson Gallery), 1958-1960, (3 folders) (Box 3, Folder 60-62)
  - Detailed Inventory of Works, 1960s, (2 folders) (Box 3, Folder 63-64)
  - Detailed Inventory of Works, Lists and Disposition Cards, 1960s, (9 folders) (Box 4, Folder 1-9)
  - Disposition Cards, 1960s, (12 folders) (Box 4, Folder 10-21)
  - Disposition Cards, 1960s, (2 folders) (Box 5, Folder 1-2)
  - Notebook, 1959-1960, (7 folders) (Box 5, Folder 3-9)
  - Notebook, Etchings and Drawings, 1959-1961, (2 folders) (Box 5, Folder 10-11)
  - Notebook, Location or Ownership of Nevelson Sculptures as known to Tom Kendall, 1961 (Box 5, Folder 12)
  - Work File of Tom Kendall, 1959-1961, (3 folders) (Box 5, Folder 13-15)
  - Unfinished Nevelson Book, 1960, (2 folders) (Box 5, Folder 16-17)
  - Prices, 1960-1961, (2 folders) (Box 5, Folder 18-19)
  - Miscellaneous, 1961-1962 (Box 5, Folder 20)
  - Itemized List for Martha Jackson Gallery Re: Extra Work on Bronze Sculptures, 1962 (Box 5, Folder 21)
  - Exhibition List and Notes, 1960s (Box 5, Folder 22)
  - Lists,undated (Box 5, Folder 23)
  - Blank Consignment Receipts (Martha Jackson Gallery), undated, (Not scanned) (Box 5, Folder 24)
- Writings, 1936-1970s, Series 5:; (Box 5; 0.1 linear feet)
  Series consists of writings by Nevelson, which shed light on different aspects of her creativity and on her ideas about art in general and her work in particular. Included are a journal of sorts in which she recorded her dreams for a two-month time period (from April 21 to June 21) in 1936; various poems and fragments of writings; various writings on art, including titled pieces, such as "The Birth of Painting (Picture Happy)" and "The Winged City," drafts of speeches on the artist Rose Newman-Wolinska and on sculpture, an article on sculpture for the Christian Science Monitor; statements which seem to have been written for The Whitney Review (1961-1962); and salutes to others, including a poem for Dorothy Dehner which appeared in an exhibition catalog for one of her shows and the draft of a short piece (possibly a speech) in honor of Merce Cunningham.
  Writings are arranged in rough chronological order.
  - Dream Journal, 1936 (Box 5, Folder 25)
  - Poems and Fragments, 1950s-1973, (3 folders) (Box 5, Folder 26-28)
  - Writings on Art, 1953-1957 (Box 5, Folder 29)
  - Artist Statements, circa 1961 (Box 5, Folder 30)
  - Salutes to Others, 1970s (Box 5, Folder 31)
- Scrapbooks, 1935-1970, Series 6:; (Boxes 5, 18-19, OV 22-27; 1.3 linear feet)
  Series consists of scrapbooks kept by Nevelson (or by someone on her behalf), documenting her early career roughly spanning from the 1930s to the mid-1950s. Also included are a scrapbook of sorts on Mike Nevelson, as well as various scrapbooks compiled by others and then presented to Nevelson as a memento of a particular event involving the artist, such as being awarded the Distinguished Service Award from State University College at Buffalo and an exhibition at the Galerie Jeanne Bucher in Paris.
  A lot of the material is duplicated in the different scrapbooks kept by Nevelson. Much of the same and related material can be found amongst printed material.
  Scrapbooks are arranged in rough chronological order. Many were removed from their original bindings at some previous time. Loose clippings and photographs of art work that were originally in scrapbooks, and were likewise removed at some previous time, are arranged in files at the end of the series. More detailed descriptions for certain scrapbooks are provided below.
  - Scrapbook, Loose Items and Pages, 1918, 1935-1955, (See Box 18; not scanned in entirety) (Box 5, Folder 32)
    Includes Nevelson's high school diploma, a drawing of Nevelson by William Zorach, drawings by Nevelson (reproductions of old masters, which she signed "Berliawsky"), and scrapbook pages of clippings and exhibition catalogs. Note attached reads "Scrapbook, original collation. Acquisition date April 1966."
  - Scrapbook, 1935-1952, (See Box 18; not scanned in entirety) (Box 5, Folder 33)
    Includes clippings (one is an article by Nevelson about her work at the Flatbush Boy's Club, the rest are mostly reviews and listings of exhibitions); announcements and catalogs for various exhibitions (including, notably, her first solo show at the Nierendorf Gallery); and a program and clippings on Mike Nevelson's performance in the play, Our Town.
  - Scrapbook, Loose Pages, 1936-1966 (bulk 1952-1956), (See OV 22-26; not scanned in entirety) (Box 5, Folder 34)
    Includes primarily clippings, exhibition announcements and catalogs from the time period 1952-1956 (much of this material is duplicated in this and other scrapbooks), as well as an exhibition catalog for the American Artists Congress show in 1936, an educational bulletin (listing a class taught by Nevelson in 1938-1939), a book of poems (in Spanish) by Alfredo Chaco, and correspondence and clippings relating to an honorary degree received in 1966.
  - Scrapbook, Loose Items and Pages, 1941-1944, 1952, circa 1960s, (See OV 27; not scanned in entirety) (Box 5, Folder 35)
    Includes, along with the more typical clippings, exhibition announcements and catalogs, photographs (stats?) of models posing in front of Nevelson art work (presumably taken sometime during the 1960s), extensive clippings on Joe Milone and his shoeshine box (discovered by Nevelson in 1942 and exhibited that same year at MOMA), and proofs of the artist photograph (where Nevelson is made up to look like a witch) which appeared in Life magazine sometime in the 1950s.
  - Scrapbook, Loose Clippings on Mike Nevelson, 1953-1956, (See Box 19) (Box 5, Folder 36)
  - Scrapbook, Distinguised Service Award from State University College at Buffalo, 1968-1969 (Box 5, Folder 37)
  - Scrapbook, Exhibition at Galerie Jeanne Bucher, 1969 (Box 5, Folder 38)
  - Scrapbook Pages (compiled by Zachary Gitlin), 1969-1970, (See Box 19) (Box 5, Folder 39)
  - Loose Clippings Originally in Scrapbooks, 1936-1958, (5 folders; not scanned) (Box 5, Folder 40-44)
  - Loose Photographs of Art Work Originally in Scrapbooks, circa 1940s-1950s, (8 folders; not scanned) (Box 5, Folder 45-52)
  - Oversize, Scrapbook, Loose Items and Pages, 1918, 1935-1955, (See Box 5, F32) (Box 18 (sol))
  - Oversize, Scrapbook, 1935-1952, (See Box 5, F33) (Box 18 (sol))
  - Oversize, Scrapbook, Loose Pages, 1936-1966 (bulk 1952-1956), (See Box 5, F34) (Box OV 22-26)
  - Oversize, Scrapbook, Loose Items and Pages, 1941-1944, 1952, circa 1960s, (See Box 5, F35) (Box OV 27)
  - Oversize, Scrapbook, Loose Clippings on Mike Nevelson, 1953-1956, (See Box 5, F36) (Box 19 (sol))
  - Oversize, Scrapbook Pages (compiled by Zachary Gitlin), 1969-1970, (See Box 5, F39) (Box 19 (sol))
- Books and Printed Material, 1916, 1930s-1979, Series 7:; (Boxes 6-13, 19, OV 28; 8 linear feet)
  Series consists of books and printed material collected by Nevelson and/or her assistants, documenting her various professional and artistic achievements throughout her career, her critical and commercial success, and her role as a personality and minor celebrity in the mass media late in her career. Books include ones given as gifts to Nevelson by friends or admirers and ones about or featuring segments on Nevelson. Printed material includes clippings from magazines and newspapers of reviews, articles, and routine listings of Nevelson's exhibits, as well as some publications featuring the same; exhibition catalogs, announcements, and invitations for Nevelson's group and solo shows, as well as some for the shows of others; and press releases, newsletters, bulletins, announcements, calendars of events, catalogs, programs and other printed material relating or referring to Nevelson or merely featuring her name in print. The extent of this material is suggestive of Nevelson's concern and effort to document and keep a record of her accomplishments.
  Printed material is arranged in rough chronological order according to type. Some material is arranged in files according to subject at the end of the series.
  - Books, 1961-1977, (11 books; not scanned) (Box 6, Folder 1)
    Titles include:
    Antologia del possible, Gastone Novelli (1962)
    Art and Sexual Politics: Women's Liberation, Women Artists, and Art History, eds. Thomas B. Hess and Elizabeth C. Baker (1973)
    Icons and Images of the Sixties, Nicolas Calas and Elena Calas (1971)
    Louise Nevelson, Arnold B. Glimcher (1972)
    Nevelson, Colette Roberts (1964)
    New Directions 17, ed. J. Laughlin (1961)
    Open Secrets: Ninety-four Women in Touch with Our Time, Barbaralee Diamonstein (1972)
    The Paper Snake, Ray Johnson (1965)
    Provacative Parallels: Naive Early Americans/International Sophisticates, Jean Lipman (1975)
    Ultime tendenze nell'arte d'oggi, Gillo Dorfles (1961)
    Ventures in Research: Lectures by the Faculty of C.W. Post Center of Long Island University, ed. Richard R. Griffith (1977)
  - Clippings, (Not scanned) (Box 6)
    - 1930s (Box 6, Folder 2)
    - 1940s, (2 folders) (Box 6, Folder 3-4)
    - 1950 (Box 6, Folder 5)
    - 1952 (Box 6, Folder 6)
    - 1953 (Box 6, Folder 7)
    - 1954 (Box 6, Folder 8)
    - 1955 (Box 6, Folder 9)
    - 1956 (Box 6, Folder 10)
    - 1957, (2 folders) (Box 6, Folder 11-12)
    - 1958, (2 folders) (Box 6, Folder 13-14)
    - 1959, (3 folders) (Box 6, Folder 15-17)
    - 1960, (3 folders) (Box 6, Folder 18-20)
    - 1961, (4 folders) (Box 6, Folder 21-24)
    - 1962, (3 folders) (Box 6, Folder 25-27)
    - 1963, (3 folders) (Box 6, Folder 28-30)
    - 1964, (3 folders) (Box 6, Folder 31-33)
    - 1965, (4 folders) (Box 7, Folder 1-4)
    - 1966, (3 folders) (Box 7, Folder 5-7)
    - 1967, (4 folders) (Box 7, Folder 8-11)
    - 1968, (3 folders) (Box 7, Folder 12-14)
    - 1969, (3 folders) (Box 7, Folder 15-17)
    - 1970, (2 folders) (Box 7, Folder 18-19)
    - 1971, (3 folders) (Box 7, Folder 20-22)
    - 1972, (3 folders) (Box 7, Folder 23-25)
    - 1973, (3 folders) (Box 7, Folder 26-28)
    - 1974, (5 folders) (Box 7, Folder 29-33)
    - 1975, (3 folders) (Box 7, Folder 34-36)
    - 1976, (6 folders) (Box 7, Folder 37-42)
    - 1977, (7 folders) (Box 8, Folder 1-7)
    - 1978, (4 folders) (Box 8, Folder 8-11)
    - 1979 (Box 8, Folder 12)
    - undated, (6 folders) (Box 8, Folder 13-18)
  - Publications, (Not scanned) (Box 8)
    - 1935 (Box 8, Folder 19)
    - 1957 (Box 8, Folder 20)
    - 1958 (Box 8, Folder 21)
    - 1959 (Box 8, Folder 22)
    - 1960 (Box 8, Folder 23)
    - 1961 (Box 8, Folder 24)
    - 1962 (Box 8, Folder 25)
    - 1963 (Box 8, Folder 26)
    - 1964 (Box 8, Folder 27)
    - 1967, (3 folders) (Box 8, Folder 28-30)
    - 1969 (Box 9, Folder 1)
    - 1970 (Box 9, Folder 2)
    - 1971 (Box 9, Folder 3)
    - 1972 (Box 9, Folder 4)
    - 1973, (3 folders) (Box 9, Folder 5-7)
    - 1974, (3 folders) (Box 9, Folder 8-10)
    - 1975, (3 folders) (Box 9, Folder 11-13)
    - 1976 (Box 9, Folder 14)
    - 1977 (Box 9, Folder 15)
    - 1978, (2 folders) (Box 9, Folder 16-17)
    - undated (Box 9, Folder 18)
  - Exhibition Catalogs, (Not scanned in entirety) (Box 9)
    - 1940s (Box 9, Folder 19)
    - 1952 (Box 9, Folder 20)
    - 1953 (Box 9, Folder 21)
    - 1955 (Box 9, Folder 22)
    - 1956 (Box 9, Folder 23)
    - 1957 (Box 9, Folder 24)
    - 1958 (Box 10, Folder 1)
    - 1959, (3 folders) (Box 10, Folder 2-4)
    - 1960, (3 folders) (Box 10, Folder 5-7)
    - 1961, (2 folders) (Box 10, Folder 8-9)
    - 1962 (Box 10, Folder 10)
    - 1963 (Box 10, Folder 11)
    - 1964, (See also Box 19) (Box 10, Folder 12)
    - 1965 (Box 10, Folder 13)
    - 1966 (Box 10, Folder 14)
    - 1967, (2 folders) (Box 10, Folder 15-16)
    - 1968 (Box 10, Folder 17)
    - 1969, (2 folders) (Box 10, Folder 18-19)
    - 1970 (Box 10, Folder 20)
    - 1971, (3 folders) (Box 10, Folder 21-23)
    - 1972, (2 folders) (Box 10, Folder 24-25)
    - 1973, (2 folders) (Box 11, Folder 1-2)
    - 1974, (4 folders) (Box 11, Folder 3-6)
    - 1975, (4 folders) (Box 11, Folder 7-10)
    - 1976, (See also Box 19) (Box 11, Folder 11)
    - 1977, (2 folders) (Box 11, Folder 12-13)
    - 1978 (Box 11, Folder 14)
    - 1979 (Box 11, Folder 15)
    - undated (Box 11, Folder 16)
  - Exhibition Announcements and Invitations (Box 11)
    - 1940s (Box 11, Folder 17)
    - 1950s (Box 11, Folder 18)
    - 1960s, (5 folders) (Box 11, Folder 19-23)
    - 1970s, (3 folders) (Box 12, Folder 1-3)
    - undated (Box 12, Folder 4)
  - Press Releases, 1944-1977, (2 folders; not scanned) (Box 12, Folder 5-6)
  - Newsletters and Bulletins, 1947-1979, (6 folders; see also Box 19; not scanned) (Box 12, Folder 7-12)
  - Exhibition Catalogs and Announcements for Others, 1951-1970, (2 folders; not scanned) (Box 12, Folder 13-14)
  - Exhibition Announcements, Posters, 1954-1977, (4 folders; see also OV 28; not scanned) (Box 12, Folder 15-18)
  - Course Catalogs for Adult Program, Great Neck Public Schools, 1955-1959, (2 folders; not scanned) (Box 12, Folder 19-20)
  - Announcements and Calendars of Events, 1958-1978, (2 folders; not scanned) (Box 12, Folder 21-22)
  - Auction Catalogs, 1961-1979, (2 folders; not scanned) (Box 12, Folder 23-24)
  - Transcript of Panel Discussion Featuring Nevelson, 1961, (Not scanned) (Box 12, Folder 25)
  - Prospectuses, 1962, (Not scanned) (Box 12, Folder 26)
  - Programs, 1963-1978, (5 folders; see also Box 19; not scanned) (Box 12, Folder 27-31)
  - Gallery and Exhibition Guides, 1964-1977, (Not scanned) (Box 12, Folder 32)
  - Reports, 1964-1977, (Not scanned) (Box 12, Folder 33)
  - Invitations, 1965-1979, (3 folders; not scanned) (Box 13, Folder 1-3)
  - Lists, 1967-1977, (Not scanned) (Box 13, Folder 4)
  - Sample of Nevelson's Portfolio of Original Serigraphs, circa 1968, (Not scanned) (Box 13, Folder 5)
  - Art Catalogs, 1969-1978, (2 folders; not scanned) (Box 13, Folder 6-7)
  - Skowhegan Award Dinner Programs, 1971-1979, (2 folders; not scanned) (Box 13, Folder 8-9)
  - Agendas, 1973, 1977, (Not scanned) (Box 13, Folder 10)
  - Clippings, Personal, 1975-1977, undated, (Not scanned) (Box 13, Folder 11)
  - Book Catalog, 1978-1979, (Not scanned) (Box 13, Folder 12)
  - Greeting Cards, Post Cards, and Drawing Pad Featuring Nevelson's Work, undated, (Not scanned) (Box 13, Folder 13)
  - Photocopied Reproductions of Nevelson Art Work, undated, (Not scanned) (Box 13, Folder 14)
  - Miscellaneous Printed Material Referring to Nevelson, 1959-1979, undated, (3 folders; not scanned) (Box 13, Folder 15-17)
  - Miscellaneous, 1916, 1957-circa 1973, undated, (Not scanned) (Box 13, Folder 18)
  - By Subject, (Not scanned) (Box 13)
    - New York Society of Ceramic Arts Exhibition, 1952 (Box 13, Folder 19)
    - Grand Central Moderns, 1957-1963 (Box 13, Folder 20)
    - Mike Nevelson, 1961-1978, (3 folders) (Box 13, Folder 21-23)
    - Venice Biennale, 1962 (Box 13, Folder 24)
    - Artists Equity Convention, 1964 (Box 13, Folder 25)
    - New York Council on the Arts, 1969 (Box 13, Folder 26)
    - "Plu Kifekler," 1969 (Box 13, Folder 27)
    - Pace Gallery, 1970s (Box 13, Folder 28)
    - Arnold Scaasi Collections, 1971 (Box 13, Folder 29)
    - Walker Art Center Exhibition, 1973 (Box 13, Folder 30)
    - Public Arts Council, 1974, 1978 (Box 13, Folder 31)
    - Sarah Scaife Gallery (Museum of Art, Carnegie Institute), 1974, (See also Box 19) (Box 13, Folder 32)
    - Rockefeller Sculpture, 1976-1978 (Box 13, Folder 33)
    - Art in Architecture Program, 1977-1979 (Box 13, Folder 34)
    - Embarcadero Center, 1977 (Box 13, Folder 35)
    - Art and Community Institute Advisory Board, 1978 (Box 13, Folder 36)
    - Little Italy Restoration Association, 1978 (Box 13, Folder 37)
    - New York Feminist Art Institute, 1979 (Box 13, Folder 38)
  - Oversize, Exhibition Catalogs, 1964, (See Box 10, F12) (Box 19 (sol))
  - Oversize, Exhibition Catalogs, 1976, (See Box 11, F11) (Box 19 (sol))
  - Oversize, Newsletters and Bulletins, 1947-1979, (Not scanned) (Box 19 (sol))
  - Oversize, Programs, 1963-1978, (Not scanned) (Box 19 (sol))
  - Oversize, By Subject, Sarah Scaife Gallery (Museum of Art, Carnegie Institute), 1974, (Not scanned) (Box 19 (sol))
  - Oversize, Exhibition Announcements, Posters, 1954-1977, (Not scanned) (Box OV 28)
- Art Work, 1905-1929, Series 8:; (Boxes 13, 20; 0.3 linear feet)
  Series consists of some of Nevelson's early art work. Included are drawings she made as a child and adolescent; watercolor copies of Old Master paintings (including a slightly changed version of the Mona Lisa), watercolor landscapes, and drawings of period furniture created while she was taking art classes in high school; and various watercolors created while she was studying art in the 1920s. Art work found here documents Nevelson's artistic tendencies as a youth and her early development as an artist, and provides an interesting contrast to the later work for which she became famous. Also included are four printing plates mounted on wood blocks, presumably used in making relief prints of certain Nevelson sculptures.
  Art work is arranged in chronological order according to type.
  - Childhood Drawings, 1905-1916 (Box 13, Folder 39)
  - Watercolors and Drawings, Old Masters, 1916, (See also Box 20) (Box 13, Folder 40)
  - Watercolors, Landscapes, 1916-1918 (Box 13, Folder 41)
  - Drawings, Period Furniture, 1918 (Box 13, Folder 42)
    Includes negatives and copy prints made by AAA for some.
  - Watercolors, Miscellaneous, 1922-1929 (Box 13, Folder 43)
    Includes a 1922 watercolor on board that may or may not be a self-portrait.
  - Watercolors, Still Life of Eggs in a Bowl, 1926 (Box 13, Folder 44)
  - Watercolors, Flowers, 1929? (Box 13, Folder 45)
  - Drawings, [Scenes of Europe?], undated (Box 13, Folder 46)
  - Printing Plates, undated, (Not scanned) (Box 13, Folder 47)
  - Oversize, Watercolors and Drawings, Old Masters, 1916, (See Box 13, F40) (Box 20 (sol))
- Photographs, circa 1903-1979, Series 9:; (Boxes 14-15, 20, OV 29; 2.3 linear feet)
  Series consists of photographs of Nevelson, her family, and her art work.
  The Photographs series is arranged into five subseries:
  9.1: Family and Personal, circa 1903-1930s
  9.2: Artist, circa 1955-1979
  9.3: Exhibitions and Installations, 1959-1979
  9.4: Art Work, 1940s-1970s
  9.5: Slides, 1950s-1970s
  - Family and Personal, circa 1903-1930s, 9.1:
    Subseries consists of photographs of the Berliawsky family, including what seems to be a portrait of Nevelson's grandparents and their sons presumably dating from the late 1800s, a portrait of her father, Isaac Berliawsky circa 1903-1904, a portrait of the Berliawsky family after their arrival in America (including Nevelson and her siblings) circa 1907, and a portrait of Nevelson's sister, Anita Berliawsky, as a young woman; Nevelson's class and team photographs, including class photographs from 1913 and 1918 (the year in which she graduated) and a photograph of Nevelson on the basketball team; portraits of Nevelson as a young girl; photographs of the Nevelson family, including a portrait of her husband, Charles, a photograph of Nevelson with her husband and his brothers, and photographs of Nevelson with her husband and son; photographs of her son, Mike, as a baby and young man; and photographs of Nevelson in New York circa 1922, in Munich circa 1931, on board a ship to Paris in 1932, and sometime during the 1930s, before she became known as an artist.
    Most files contain copy prints and negatives of the photographs made by AAA. Files are arranged in chronological order.
    - Berliawsky Family, circa 1903-1907, and undated (Box 14, Folder 1)
    - Class and Team Photographs, 1913-1919 (Box 14, Folder 2)
    - Portraits of Louise Nevelson as a Young Girl, circa 1915-1920 (Box 14, Folder 3)
    - Nevelson Family, 1920s (Box 14, Folder 4)
    - Mike Nevelson, 1920s-1930s (Box 14, Folder 5)
    - Louise Nevelson, circa 1922-1930s, (See also Box 20) (Box 14, Folder 6)
    - Oversize, Louise Nevelson, circa 1922-1930s, (See Box 14, F6) (Box 20 (sol))
  - Artist, circa 1955-1979, undated, 9.2: